import { SquareRoot, superscript, subscript, BoldText, ItalicText, Fraction, ShortFraction, LongFraction, MixedFraction, Isotopes } from "@/mathnotation"

const path = "@/assets/images/pastquestions-figures/integratedscience/integratedscienceA/integratedscience-"

export const INTEGRATEDSCIENCEA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. The volumetric flask is used in the laboratory to",
A: "prepare standard solution",
B: "separate a mixture of immiscible liquids",
C: "carry out simple distillation",
D: "dry substances",
answer: "A. prepare standard solution",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. The internal diameter of a wedding ring could be measured most accurately using a",
A: "half-metre rule",
B: "tape measure",
C: "micrometer screw gauge",
D: "Vernier calipers.",
answer: "D. vernier callipers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. Which of the following organism transmits the protozoa which causes trypanosomiasis in cattle",
A: "Louse",
B: "Mosque",
C: "Tick",
D: "Tsetse fly",
answer: "D. Tsetse fly",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. Biological control of malaria involves",
A: "draining breeding grounds of mosquitoes",
B: "spraying surfaces on which mosquitoes settle with insecticides",
C: "introducing fish into ponds to feed on larvae of mosquitoes",
D: "burying empty cans.",
answer: "C. introducing fish into ponds to feed on larvae of mosquitoes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Water is referred to as universal solvent because it",
A: "dissolves most substances",
B: "changes blue litmus solution to red",
C: "reacts with base to produce salt",
D: "has pH of 7",
answer: "A. dissolves most substances",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. The heat energy needed to convert a quantity of liquid at its boiling point to vapour is referred to as",
A: "latent heat of fusion",
B: "specific latent heat of fusion",
C: "latent heat of vaporization",
D: "specific latent heat of vaporization",
answer: "C. latent heat of vaporization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. A feeding association in which one-partner benefits while the other losses is known as",
A: "commensalism",
B: "mutualism",
C: "parasitism",
D: "symbiosis",
answer: "C. parasitism",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Which of the following symptoms is associated with anthracnose in cassava",
A: "Rotting of tubers",
B: "Reddish colour of older leaves",
C: "Wilting of the leaves",
D: "Irregular spots on older leaves.",
answer: "C. Wilting of the leaves",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. Which of the following activities could control fungal diseases in a backyard garden \nI. Planting resistant varieties \nII. Practising good farm sanitation \nIII. Destroying affected plants by burning",
A: "I only",
B: "I and II only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III only",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. The contraction of the biceps muscle in humans is likely to result in",
A: "straightening of the forearm",
B: "bending of the foream",
C: "contraction of the triceps",
D: "movement of the scapula towards the sternum",
answer: "B. bending of the forearm",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. Alpha decay involves the emission of",
A: "electrons",
B: "neutrons",
C: "helium nuclei",
D: "gamma rays.",
answer: "C. helium nuclei",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. Hydrolysis of fats and oils in the presence of a base results in the production of",
A: "soapy detergent and glycerol",
B: "soapless detergent and glycerol",
C: "soapy detergent and alcohol",
D: "soap and fatty acid",
answer: "A. soapy detergent and glycerol",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. The role of oxygen in seed germination is to",
A: "provide energy for cell division and growth",
B: "soften the seed coat",
C: "dissolve the stored food",
D: "transport food substances to site of growth",
answer: "A. provide energy for cell division and growth",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Which of the diagram below illustrates a body in a stable equilibrium",
A: ".",
B: ".",
C: ".",
D: ".",
answer: "B. ****",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. Liming the soil improves its fertility by",
A: "neutralizing soil acidity",
B: "decreasing the activity of soil microorganism",
C: "improving soil structure",
D: "reducing soil erosion",
answer: "A. neutralizing soil acidity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. Radioisotopes are used in \nI treatment of cancer \nII. Food preservation \nIII. Pest control \nIV. Plant breeding \nWhich of the statements above are correct",
A: "I, II and III only",
B: "I, II and IV only",
C: "II, III and IV only",
D: "I, III, III and IV only",
answer: "D. I, II, III and IV",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. A 50 g sample of garden soil weighs 45 g after drying in an oven. Determine the percentage moisture content of the sample.",
A: "95%",
B: "20 %",
C: "11%",
D: "10%",
answer: "D. 10%",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. Ectopic pregnancy in humans may result in  \nI. rupture of the fallopian tube \nII. Bleeding \nIII. Weakness of the abdominal muscles \nWhich of the statements above are correct",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III only",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. Given that the Avogadro’s constant is 6.02 x 1023, determine the number of atoms in 0.01 moles of a substance",
A: "6.02 x 1020 atoms",
B: "6.02 x 1020 atoms",
C: "6.02 1023 atoms",
D: "6.02 x 1024 atoms",
answer: "B. 6",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. An object is place 150 cm in front of a vertical plane mirror. The image formed is",
A: "same size as the object",
B: "situated 150 cm from the object",
C: "real and erect",
D: "diminished",
answer: "A. same size as the object",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. Which of the following benefits could be derived by a farmer from the practice of mulching \nI. Control of growth of weeds \nII. Improvement in soil structure \nIII. Reduction of soil erosion",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III only",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. One of the functions of the human vertebral column is to",
A: "enclose and protect the brain",
B: "form a hollow to accommodate the heart",
C: "hold the lungs in position",
D: "support the head",
answer: "D. support the head",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. A force of 60 N was used to raise a load of 300 N. determine the mechanical advantage of the machine",
A: "5",
B: "60",
C: "360",
D: "18000",
answer: "A. 5",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. The IUPAC name of the compound with the formula Cu(NO3)2 is",
A: "copper (II) trioxonitrate (IV)",
B: "copper (I) trioxonitrate (V)",
C: "copper trioxonitrate (IV)",
D: "copper (IV) trioxonitrate (III)",
answer: "A. copper(II) trioxonitrate(V)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. The function of the pancreatic juice in the digestive system of humans is to break down \nI. starch to sugars \nII. Proteins to peptides \nIII. Fats to fatty acids and glycerol \nIV. Peptides to amino acids \nWhich of the statements above are correct",
A: "I and II only",
B: "III and IV only’",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "II, III and IV only",
answer: "C. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. Which of the following steps are required in the scientific approach to problem solving \nI. Identifying a problem \nII. Carrying out experiment \nIII. Analyzing results of experiment \nIV. Drawing conclusions.",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I, II and III only",
C: "II, III and IV only",
D: "I, II, III and IV only",
answer: "D. I, II, III and IV",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. Grafting is a technique in crop production in which a",
A: "scion and a bud are joined together",
B: "scion and a root stock are joined together",
C: "stem and a root stock are joined together",
D: "stem and a scion are joined together",
answer: "B. scion and a root stock are joined together",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. Which of the following statements about a stepdown transformer is /are correct. It has \nI. more turns in the secondary coil than in the primary coil \nII. less turns in the secondary coil than in the primary coil \nIII. higher voltage in the primary coil than in the secondary coil. \n",
A: "I only",
B: "II only",
C: "I and III only",
D: "II and III only",
answer: "D. II and III only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. Nerve impulses are carried into a nerve cell in humans by the",
A: "synapse",
B: "dendrite",
C: "mitochondrion",
D: "myelin sheath",
answer: "B. dendrite",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. A 500 cm3 of a solution contains 0.50 mol of HCL. Determine the molar concentration of the solution",
A: "0.03 M",
B: "0.25 M",
C: "0.50 M",
D: "1.00M",
answer: "D. 1",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Which of the following statements explain why a boat floats in water. The boat floats because \nI. the upthrust on it equals the weight of water it displaces. \nII. its average density is less than that of the water \nIII. upthrust is equal to the volume of water displaced",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. Lack of calcium in the soil will result in",
A: "stunted growth of plants",
B: "chlorosis in leaves",
C: "retardation in seed formation",
D: "yellowing of tips and margins of older leaves",
answer: "A. stunted growth of plants",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Which of the following chemical compound gives off annonia gas when heated with calcium hydroxide",
A: "NaOH",
B: "Na2CO3",
C: "NH2Cl",
D: "K2SO4",
answer: "C. NH4Cl",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. The rate of evaporation of a liquid could be increased by",
A: "decreasing the surface area",
B: "reducing the temperature",
C: "maintaining the temperature",
D: "removing the vapour as it forms.",
answer: "D. removing the vapour as it forms",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. Which of the following elements is a macro plant nutrient",
A: "Boron",
B: "Copper",
C: "Managanese",
D: "Phosphorus",
answer: "D. Phosphorus",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. The temperature of a body is 60C. the body’s temperature in Kelvin is",
A: "60K",
B: "213 K",
C: "273K",
D: "333K",
answer: "D. 333 K",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. Which of the following properties are associated with ionic compound \nI. They are soluble in water \nII. They are high melting points \nIII. They conduct electricity in aqueous solution",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. A vehicle moving at a velocity of 20m s-1 decelerates to rest at 5 m s-1. Determine the distance it moves from the point of deceleration to rest.",
A: "20 m",
B: "40 m",
C: "60 m",
D: "80 m",
answer: "B. 40 m",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. Duralumin is made of an aluminum and",
A: "lead",
B: "iron",
C: "copper",
D: "zinc",
answer: "C. copper",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. Which of the following functions is /are associated with the endoplasmic reticulum of a living cell \nI. Supports the ribosomes \nII. Provides large surface area for chemical reaction \nIII.. Provides mechanical support to the cytoplasm",
A: "I only",
B: "I and II only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II, and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. An organism in the production of alcoholic beverages is",
A: "bacterium",
B: "protozoan",
C: "virus",
D: "yeast.",
answer: "D. yeast",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. Which of the following are associated with farm yard ? it \nI. is easy to prepare \nII. Absorbs and retain moisture \nIII. Encourage rapid weed growth \nA. I and II only",
B: "III and IV only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "II, III and IV only",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. The primary functions of the Eustachian tube in mammalian ear is",
A: "protect the ear drum",
B: "equalize pressure on both sides of the ear",
C: "balance the human body",
D: "amplify sound",
answer: "B. equalize pressure on the both sides of the ear drum",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. Structured hydrocarbons are characterized by the presence of",
A: "single covalent bond between carbons atom s",
B: "double covalent bond between carbons atoms",
C: "triple covalent bond between carbons atoms",
D: "single covalent bonds between carbons and hydrogen atoms",
answer: "A. single covalent bond between carbon atoms",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. Which of the following groups of characteristics in humans is classified as phenotype?",
A: "Eye colour and height",
B: "Eye colour and blood group",
C: "Height and sickle cell",
D: "Blood group and height",
answer: "A. Eye colour and height",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. The S. I unit of potential difference is",
A: "ampere",
B: "ohm",
C: "volts",
D: "watts",
answer: "C. volts",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. Magnesium is classified as a metal because it",
A: "has low density",
B: "has high tensile strength",
D: "is a solid",
answer: "B. has high tensile strength",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. Which of the following colours is a primary colour",
A: "cyan",
B: "Green",
C: "Purple",
D: "Violet",
answer: "B. Green",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. Which of the following are statements are reasons why farmers breed rabbits \nI. Fast growth rate  \nII. Good litter size  \nIII. Large carcass",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. Which of the following plants seeds undergo hypogeal germination",
A: "Cowpea",
B: "Flamboyant",
C: "Maize",
D: "Castor oils",
answer: "C. Maize",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},



]